It’s more than 384,000km from Earth. We can see it most nights.
它距离地球超过38.4万公里，我们在大多数夜晚都能看到它，而且它根本不是奶酪做的！
And it’s not made of cheese!
没错，我说的就是月球。
I am, of course, talking about the Moon.
在探索这颗悬浮在太空中的天然卫星的征程中，宇航员们已经取得了巨大进展。
Astronauts have taken giant steps to explore this natural satellite floating in space, but despite it being out of reach for most of us, it still moves us in mysterious ways.
尽管对我们大多数人来说，月球遥不可及，但它仍以神秘的方式影响着我们。
The Moon, obviously, provides moonlight.
显然，月球能带来月光。
A full moon, seen roughly once a month, can light up our way on an otherwise dark night.
满月大约每月出现一次，它能在漆黑的夜晚照亮我们前行的路。
But while this lunar light can be impressive to look at, it can affect our sleeping patterns.
不过，尽管月色看起来令人赞叹，它却会影响我们的睡眠规律。
One study showed that during or around the full moon, those studied spent less time in deep sleep, slept for less time and reported having poorer sleep, despite sleeping in a dark room not exposed to moonlight.
一项研究表明，在满月期间或前后，即使研究对象身处没有月光照射的黑暗房间里，他们的深度睡眠时间和总睡眠时间也会减少，而且睡眠质量也更差。
There are many theories about how the Moon can affect other things too.
关于月球如何影响其他事物，也存在诸多理论。
One study suggested animals are more likely to bite us during a full moon.
有研究指出，动物在满月期间更容易咬人。
And many moons ago, it was thought the Moon induced lunacy – the word derives from the Latin word ‘lunaticus’, meaning ‘moonstruck’, and evolved from the idea that celestial changes could cause periods of insanity.
很久以前，人们还认为月球会引发精神失常——“lunacy”这个词源自拉丁语“lunaticus”，意为“受月亮影响的”，这个说法源于“天体变化可能导致精神失常发作”的观点。
Even winemakers look to the Moon when planting and pruning grapevines.
就连酿酒师在种植和修剪葡萄藤时也会参照月相。
They will avoid a full moon at all costs because, although the added moisture in the soil at this time may give a fuller and juicier grape, the additional water is thought to dilute the taste of the fruit, which results in a less successful vintage.
他们会不惜一切代价避开满月时段，因为尽管此时土壤中额外的水分能让葡萄长得更饱满多汁，但这些多余的水分会稀释果实的风味，进而酿造出品质欠佳的葡萄酒。
The Moon might affect our behaviour too.
月球或许也会影响人类的行为。
Writing about this for BBC Future, Claudia Hammond explains one interesting theory. Just as the Moon’s gravitational pull affects the tides, it exerts its influence on the water in our bodies.
克劳迪娅·哈蒙德在为BBC未来频道撰写相关文章时，阐释了一个有趣的理论：就像月球引力会影响潮汐一样，它也会对人体中的水分产生作用。
But she points out “the Moon is smaller than the Earth, so its gravitational pull is correspondingly less powerful.
但她也指出：“月球比地球小，所以其引力也相应较弱。
What’s more, it exerts the same force on us regardless of whether it’s new or full.”
此外，无论新月还是满月，月球对人体施加的引力都是相同的。”
Research into ancient myths about the effects of the lunar cycle on us is ongoing.
关于月相周期对人类影响的古老传说，相关研究仍在进行中。
So, like the Moon being made of cheese, we must be careful what we believe!
所以，就像“月球是奶酪做的”这种说法一样，我们对听到的各种观点都应该保持审慎！